capilanou.ca 2019-12-08

# Privacy Statement - Capilano University

## Introduction and purpose

Capilano University (the “University”) is committed to protecting the privacy and confidentiality of personal information.  All personal information that is collected by the University, whether through this website (www.capilanou.ca) or by other means, is managed according to the BC [Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act](http://www.bclaws.ca/Recon/document/ID/freeside/96165_00 "Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act") (“FIPPA”) and applicable University policies.

The purpose of this privacy statement is to disclose how personal information may be collected and used through this website.

## Scope

This privacy statement describes the privacy practices for [www.capilanou.ca](http://www.capilanou.ca/ "www.capilanou.ca") and all microsites based on this domain. The statement applies solely to information collected by these websites.

## Collection and use

“Personal Information” is recorded information about an identifiable individual, such as an individual’s name, address, birth date, email address and phone number. This website does not automatically gather personal information from you. This information is only obtained if you provide it voluntarily.

### Information provided voluntarily in email and web forms

Some personal information, including but not limited to name and email address, may be provided voluntarily by users of University websites to request services such as newsletter sign up, image download, online surveys, and other similar services.

Personal information provided voluntarily in an email or by filling out a form will not be used or disclosed to anyone except University personnel who need the information for legitimate business purposes such as responding to a message or request.

### Information collected automatically

When you visit our website, the web server automatically collects a small amount of information to facilitate the operation and security of our website. Some of the information collected does not identify who you are. Other information, such as your domain name or Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, may identify you depending on the naming standards followed by your internet service provider. If this concerns you, you may wish to ask them about their policies and practices.

While we make no attempt to link the information captured to the identity of individuals, the information collected automatically may include the following:

  * The IP Address and domain name used for the computer accessing the website;
  * The type of browser and operating system;
  * The type of device (e.g. iPhone, Android, mobile or tablet);
  * The date and time of the visit; and
  * The web pages or services accessed.

Information collected automatically is maintained in a secure environment.  Summary reports will be used by the University for purposes such as assessing system performance, monitoring traffic patterns, improving web services, and website management.  We do not track or record information about specific individuals and their visits.

## Disclosure

Where personal information is collected by the University, the information will be collected in compliance with FIPPA and will adhere to University policies. We do not sell, trade or disclose any of your personal information to third parties without your consent or legal authority. We will not disclose your personal information for any purpose other than the purpose for which it was collected without your prior written consent unless the disclosure is permitted under FIPPA or other applicable legislation.

## **Cookies**

A “cookie” is a small file that a website creates when you visit the site.  It can track and store information about you such as how and when you use a site and which site you visited immediately before.  Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer.  Our website may use session cookies which are stored in temporary memory and are not retained after you sign out or close the browser session.

If you are concerned about the use of cookies, you can refer to the help information in your browser software for information on how to disable cookies. If you wish to delete cookies from your machine, consult your browser’s help files for instructions on how to do so.

## Google Analytics

In order to improve website performance and user experience, our website uses Google Analytics. All data collected by Google Analytics remains anonymous and non-personally identifiable. We will never merge this data with personal information, nor use the data for any purpose other than to analyze usage of the website.

The University reserves the right to grant access to our Google Analytics implementation to our contracted third-party consultants for the purpose of streamlining our web analytics processes. Google Analytics may store information outside of Canada where it may not receive the same privacy protection it receives in Canada. Summary reports will be used to improve usability on our sites and to help support the online needs of visitors. You may opt-out of Google Analytics data collection at any time by using one of the available opt-outs for the web. For more information about Google Analytics security and privacy, please see [Google Analytics Solutions](https://www.google.com/analytics/analytics/#?modal_active=none "Google Analytics Solutions").

## Links to third party sites

University websites contain links to other sites and we provide these links as a referent to help you identify and locate other Internet resources that you may find of interest.  While the University endeavors to link to other sites that have similarly high standards and respect for privacy, we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other websites.

## Access to information

You have the right of access to and a right to request correction of your own personal information. You may email us at [privacy@capilanou.ca](mailto:privacy@capilanou.ca "privacy@capilanou.ca") to:

  * See what personal information has been collected about you, if any;
  * Change/correct any personal information we have about you;
  * Have us delete any personal information we have about you; and/or
  * Express any concern you have about our use of your personal information.

## Security

Our password protocols and encryption software are routinely updated to maximize protection of personal and other information.  While we strive to protect personal information, please note that no Internet data transmission is completely secure.

## More information

Questions or concerns regarding our management of this privacy statement may be directed to the [Privacy Office](mailto:privacy@capilanou.ca).
